Adrian Grimm

https://adriangrimm.com https://github.com/usmcamgrimm Massillon, OH | (386)438-3487 usmcamgrimm@gmail.com

Profile

I am a front-end developer passionate about writing clear, semantic HTML, CSS and JavaScript that follow design and Web Accessibility standards. My experience with front-end frameworks includes React and Gatsby and I have an extensive background in open source development using Git. A Marine Corps veteran, I value teamwork and collaboration and I am motivated to parallel the growth of my skills with the company's product.

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

SQL

Git

Accessibility

JAMStack

React

Gatsby

Education

Vets Who Code - Front-End Developer Bootcamp **Stark State College** - Certificate, Web Design & Development | GPA: 4.0 Sept 2019 – Jan 2020

May 2020

Experience

Securitas Electronic Security: Senior Programming Specialist

Feb 2016 - Present

Provided technical support for technicians in the service and installation of alarm and video equipment.

Diebold, Inc.: Senior Programming Specialist

Oct 2013 - Feb 2016

- Assisted field technicians with detailed technical support for access control systems.
- Utilized and maintained a SQL database for a card access system, and generated monthly, quarterly, and on-demand reports.

Diebold, Inc.: EMC Dispatch Representative

Aug 2012 - Oct 2013

• Successfully and efficiently responded to alarm signals generated by automated monitoring software.

United American Security: Lieutenant / Site Supervisor

Aug 2011 – Aug 2012

- Effectively led, managed, and trained a team of corporate security officers assigned under my direction.
- Created and provisioned access cards for Diebold associates and contract employees.

Corrections Corporation of America: Correctional Officer

Feb 2010 - July 2011

Henderson, TX and Lake City, FL

- Exercised care, custody, and control of offenders assigned to serve sentences of incarceration.
- Assisted in multiple inmate cell extractions as a member of the Special Operations Response Team.

United States Marine Corps: Towed Artillery Systems Technician

Jan 2002 - Jan 2010

Billets included: Instructor, Battalion Ordnance Officer, Battalion Ordnance Chief, Artillery Section Head

- 2007, Fallujah, Iraq: Ensured security for Battalion and Company level staff.
- 2002-2008, Camp Lejeune, NC: Effectively managed readiness of the Battalion's artillery assets.
- 2003, 2005, Iraq, various locations: Instrumental in maintaining unit combat effectiveness.
- 2008-2010, APG, MD: Effectively trained and mentored entry-level Marines as Artillery Repairmen.